PETER STEVENS

07727 900494 | Peterstevens510@gmail.com | https://github.com/Thatguy560 - Github | https://thatguy560.github.io/ - Online Portfolio

Profile

I'm a Junior Developer and Makers Academy alumni, striving for a position where I'm constantly learning and developing my skills and knowledge in software development. My passion for technology and problem solving encouraged my research into a career in this industry. I chose Makers as my training provider because of their great track record and emphasis on practical, real world experience, pair programming and holistic development. Makers furthered my skills with Ruby and Javascript, taught me the importance of effective Github collaboration practices and reinforced my skills with teamwork and problem solving. For a list of all the projects I've worked on, please visit my GitHub linked in the header to see some examples.

Projects

Road To Discovery

App which allows a user to generate a playlist within a short period of time. Tech Stackincludes React, Node, Javascript, Spotify Web API, Travis CI, Heroku https://github.com/Team-react/Playlist_App https://road-to-discovery.herokuapp.com/

IsItBusyOrNot

App which allows users to search for a location and see how busy it is. A Hackathon team project on the brief of COVID-19, made in 2 and a half days. Tech Stackincludes React, Express.js, Twitter API, OpenLayers API, Heroku https://is-it-busy-or-not.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/Peter2-71828/IsItBusyOrNot

Bank Tech Test

Tech Test built over a 3 day period, using irb you can make deposits, withdrawals, check the balance of your account and print a statement. Tech Stackincludes Ruby, RSpec https://github.com/Thatguy560/Banktechtest

Gilded Rose Refactoring

Another Tech test that involved cloning a repository, reading it, writing some tests and then refactoring the legacy code. Tech Stackincludes Ruby, RSpec https://github.com/Thatguy560/GildedRose-Refactoring-Kata

Skills

- Languages & Frameworks Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Rails, React, jQuery, Sinatra, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL
- Practices Object Oriented Programming, TDD, MVC, Domain-driven design, Agile/XP, RSpec, Jasmine
- **Soft Skills** Communication, Attention To Detail, Problem Solving, Adaptability, Teamwork

Education

Makers Academy

01/2020 - 05/2020

Software Developer Bootcamp, London Liverpool Street

My studies with Makers Academy helped establish the basic skills required for a career in software development. This education has provided a good understanding of the subject and given me the confidence to tackle increasingly complex projects. My current language of choice is Ruby but I also have a working knowledge of Javascript.

BPP 07/2017 - 11/2018

AAT Level 3

Kaplan Financial 10/2015 - 10/2016

AAT Level 2

Chace Community Sixth Form 09/2012 - 08/2015

A2 Level: Maths **B**, Physics **C**, Chemistry **D** AS Level: Maths **B**, Physics **C**, Chemistry **C**

Chace Community School 09/2007 - 06/2012

9 GCSEs (Including English & Maths Grades A* - C

Employment History

English Rural

03/2019 - 10/2019

Temporary Finance Assistant, Westminster

- Within a few weeks I was adept at using 'SDM Housing Software'
- Effective communication with suppliers to enable invoice payments were handled correctly.

Finance Apprentice

03/2017 - 01/2019

The Association of Commonwealth Universities, Euston

- Trusted to manage multimillion payments.
- Relished the opportunity to work with a variety of people from different ages and cultural backgrounds.

Trainee Accounts Technician

10/2015 - 10/2016

Xhi Accounting Limited , Caledonian Road

- Worked effectively with good team practices and pragmatic time management. We used Trello to manage tasks and Harvest software for time tracking.
- Liaised with clients to produce accounts and perform bank reconciliations.

Find Me Online





LinkedIn

Online Portfolio